mapsofindia.com 2019-07-08

# Privacy Policy - MapsofIndia.com

**1\. What identifiable information is collected from me?**  
MapsOfIndia.com may collect information in several ways from different parts of our network of Web sites.   
MapsOfIndia.com may ask you for personal information at times, including, but not limited to, when you enter in a contest or promotion sponsored by MapsOfIndia.com and/or our other contracted partners; when you browse for travel arrangements looking at the images on the site and when you report a problem with one of our sites or services. MapsOfIndia.com occasionally may also ask site user to complete surveys that are use for internal research. Wherever MapsOfIndia.com collects personal information an effort is made to include a link to this Privacy Policy on that page. 

**2\. What are cookies and how MapsOfIndia.com uses them?**  
As combined part of offering and providing customised and personalised services, MapsOfIndia.com may use cookies to store and track your information. A cookie is a miniscule amount of data that is sent to your browser from a Web server that may be stored on your computer's hard drive. 

Maps of India never stores your access credentials (User-Name and Password) of your social media accounts like Facebook, Twitter etc. on its servers. Maps of India authenticates your requests using Oauth, under which you pass your access credentials directly on the respective social media sites - Facebook, Twitter etc. thus limiting the possibility of any unauthorized use of your access credentials.

**3\. Who is collecting information?**  
When you are visiting a MapsOfIndia.com site and are asked for personal information, you are sharing that information for use by MapsOfIndia.com alone, unless it is specifically stated otherwise. Some MapsOfIndia.com services may be offered in conjunction with a third partner. In order to provide this service to you, it may be necessary for us to share your personal information with our partner company. In such cases you will be notified prior to the time of the data collection or transfer. Where as if you do not want your data to be shared, you can choose not to allow the transfer of such data by not using that particular service at all. 

Sometime promotions that run on MapsOfIndia.com network sites may be sponsored by companies other than MapsOfIndia.com or may be co-sponsored by MapsOfIndia.com and another company. Some or all data collected during such a promotion may be shared with the sponsor. In the event of data being shared, you will be notified prior to the time of data collection or transfer. So you can decide whether to participate in the promotion, if you don't want your data to be shared. 

Please be advised that MapsOfIndia.com advertisers or Web sites that have links on our site may collect personally identifiable information about you. Such information practices of those Web sites linked to MapsOfIndia.com are expressly not covered by this privacy statement. 

**4\. With who else MapsOfIndia.com will share my information?**  
As a thumb rule, MapsOfIndia.com will not wilfully disclose any of your personally identifiable information except when we have your permission or under extraneous circumstances, such as when we believe in good faith that the law requires it or under the circumstances described below. Described herein under are some of the ways that your information may be shared or disclosed. 

Sponsors & Business Partners: MapsOfIndia.com may disclose your personal information to business partners or sponsors, but this is specifically and expressly described to you at the time of data collection or prior to transferring the data. Some or all data collected during a MapsOfIndia.com promotion may be shared with a sponsor. If a part of personally identifying data about you will be shared, we will tell you before we collect or transfer the data. 

During many promotions offers you may be requested for additional information from sponsors. By requesting more information, you give MapsOfIndia.com permission to transfer your personal information to the sponsor so they can fulfil your request. In majority of instances, only your email address will be shared. 

Third Party Data & Data Comparisons: Under confidentiality agreements, MapsOfIndia.com may match user information with third party data. Also, MapsOfIndia.com discloses patterned user statistics in order to describe our services to prospective partners, advertisers, and or other third parties, and for other lawful purposes. 

**Miscellaneous:** MapsOfIndia.com may also disclose user information in such cases where we have reason to believe that disclosure of this information is necessary to identify, contact or bring legal action against someone who may be causing injury to or interference with (either intentionally or unintentionally) Compare Infobase Limited's or MapsOfIndia.com's rights or property, other MapsOfIndia.com users, or anyone else that could be harmed by such activities. MapsOfIndia.com may disclose user information when we believe in good faith that the law or law-enforcing agency requires it. 

**5\. Do I have choices or controls regarding collection, use, and distribution of my identifiable information?**

Upon your express interest about receiving offers or information from MapsOfIndia.com and our partners under confidentiality, may occasionally send you e-mail or postal mail about products and services that we feel may be of interest to you and only if you indicated that you do not object to these offers. 

Any time you can easily unsubscribe from MapsOfIndia.com's mailing list and no longer receive such offers and mailings. 

On some types of MapsOfIndia.com promotions, we will ask for your email address in order to update you on your score, entries, and status in prize drawings. Your participation in these types of promotions, may automatically enlist you to receive promotion-related email. Sometime these promotion-related emails may include targeted advertisements. 

You also have choices with respect to cookies. By modifying your browser preferences, you have the choice to accept all cookies, to be notified when a cookie is set, or to reject all cookies. If you choose to reject all cookies you will be unable to use some of MapsOfIndia.com services that require the use of cookies in order to participate. 

MapsOfIndia.com as a policy does not sell or rent your information to anyone. We will notify you at the time of data collection or transfer if your data will be shared with a third party and you will always have the option of not permitting the transfer. You can choose not to use a particular service or not to participate in certain promotions or contests, if you do not wish to allow such data sharing. 

Mapsofindia.com has contracted with third party vendors, including Google, who may use cookies to serve ads based on a User's prior visits to Mapsofindia.com Google's use of Double Click cookie enables it and its partners to server ads Users based on their visits to MOW. Users may opt out of the use of Double Click cookie for internet based advertising by visiting the [Ad Preference Manager ](https://adssettings.google.com/u/0/authenticated?hl=en)or [here](https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout/), [Tribal Fusion Opt Out ](http://exponential.com/privacy/opt-out/), [Taboola Opt Out](https://www.taboola.com/privacy-policy#optout), or [NAI Opt Out ](http://optout.networkadvertising.org/#%21/).

we have listed Ad Preference Manager, Tribal Fusion, Taboola and NAI Opt Out. Kindlt check whether we have allowed other advertisers and if the response is in affirmative, we are required to list those advertisers also.

Further, we are required to ask the advertisers whether they are complying with the EU GDPR norms.

**6\. How much protected is my personal financial information?**   
To keep your personal financial information private is vital and important to us. As with all personal information, MapsOfIndia.com will never rent or sell your personal financial information. Your use of certain services or features, known to us, may help us to offer you better and more relevant content and advertisements. Yet as with all personally identifiable information, we do not make this available to any third parties without your permission. 

Please note that there may be places on the MapsOfIndia.com network of Web sites where you can transmit credit card information in order to complete a purchase transaction or for verification purposes. Any time we ask for a credit card number we transmit that credit card number in an encrypted format. We use best industry-standard, SSL (secure socket layer) encryption technology. This sophisticated encryption process ensures that prying eyes are unable to decode your personal data when it travels from your computer to ours. 

**7\. What security precautions are in place to protect the loss, misuse, or alteration of information?**   
It may not be a norm but the fact remains that no data transmission over the Internet can be guaranteed to be 100% secure always. As a result, while we strive to protect your personal information, MapsOfIndia.com cannot ensure or warrant the total security of any information you transmit to us or for our online products purchase or services, and you do so at your own risk. But once we receive your transmission, we strive and make our best effort to ensure its security on our systems. 

**8\. What else should I know about my privacy?**   
Do keep in mind that whenever you voluntarily disclose personal information online - for example on message boards, through email, on mailing lists or in chat areas - that information can be seen and collected and used by others. In nutshell, if you post personal information online that is accessible to the other public, you may receive unsolicited messages from other parties in return. 

Finally, you are solely responsible for maintaining the secrecy of your passwords and/or any registration information. Please be careful and responsible on your own whenever you're online. 

**9\. Is there any children's privacy?**  
Yes, the safety of children is very important to us. Children should always ask a parent for permission before sending personal information to MapsOfIndia.com or to anyone online for that matter. MapsOfIndia.com does not share personal information about users under the age of 13 with third parties under any circumstances unless there is a special situation and such information is requested by law enforcing agency and we do not sell or rent personal information about any of our users, regardless of their age. In addition, MapsOfIndia.com will not send any direct email offers to users who indicate they are under the age of 13 without first obtaining their parents' permission. MapsOfIndia.com is an information site and we encourage the children to use the same and as a policy we never display by way of direct or any third party agreement, any pornographic material. 

**10\. Additional Information**   
For any clarification regarding this Privacy Policy, you may contact Maps of India by sending an e - mail to 

[operations@MapsOfIndia.com](mailto:operations@MapsOfIndia.com) with "Regarding Privacy Policy" in the subject line. 

Last Updated on : May 24, 2018
